[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
EPISODE 11
UNCOOL!
...the start of summer break for many
students in our area...
SUMMER BREAK
Oh.
- [muffled] Good morning.
- Morning.
[Taiki] Oh, man.
Looks like we're alone together.
But it'll be weird if I just leave.
Do you have practice today?
Um, what was that?
Practice.
Uh...
[gargles, spits]
Badminton practice?
You're not wearing your sports gear.
Oh. Uh. Yeah.
But I'm meeting friends
at the library later,
so we can do summer-break homework.
That's why I'm wearing this.
[Chinatsu] Oh. Sounds like a good time.
[chuckles] I might
have to steal your idea.
Well, good luck, then.
Yeah thanks.
[Taiki] She's acting super normal.
EIMEI PRIVATE HIGH SCHOOL
- I guess that's that.
- [Haryu] Yo.
Hey!
I should just forget about it and move on.
So, I won't do anything like that again,
going forward.
[Taiki] I'm right back to where I started.
[snoring]
- [Taiki] No sleeping, Hina!
- I wasn't asleep!
We all made the time to get together,
so let's focus up and work.
Yeah, but I heard that sleep is when
your brain makes all your memories stick.
So you were sleeping.
I'm looking at all these numbers,
but I don't get any of it.
No one taught me this stuff.
Well, actually, they did.
Well, if you just substitute that for x...
- [boy] Yo dude.
- What?
- So...
- Look at Ito, he's making a move.
It's about time.
He's been crushing on her forever.
They won't run into each other
anymore because of summer break,
so today's the day.
At least get her number, dude.
- [Taiki exclaiming]
- [Kyo] Just do your homework.
[Taiki] I guess I haven't thought
about it before but...
everyone's got a crush on someone.
[Taiki] What's up, slacker.
I'm not a slacker, I'm here
'cause I'm fresh out of energy.
[Taiki] Doesn't mean
you should sleep here.
Oh, look who just sat down.
Uh-huh, 'cause we can't have
drinks in the library.
[gulps] Ah, that hits the spot.
[girl 1 squeals] I can't believe
the fireworks festival is next week!
[girl 2] Yeah! We're all
still going together right?
Of course! And let's invite Sasaki.
[chuckles] For sure!
In junior high,
we went to the festival together.
Yeah, that was all Saijo's idea.
I wonder how that kid's doing.
[Taiki] He's at San High,
and joined a band.
I can totally see that.
That's also about the time
when you and I started talking.
Was it?
[Saijo] There's a fireworks festival
next week!
We'll be classmates
for all of junior high,
so let's commemorate it and go together!
- [boy] Sounds good to me!
- You gonna go Hina?
[Hina] I want a candy apple.
I guess you're going.
But don't we have practice that day?
It'll be fine. Practice ends at 6:00.
You can only get candy apples
at festivals like this!
Okay. Raise your hand if you're going!
- Me!
- Oh! [groans]
- All right then...
- Oops. Sorry about that, Taiki.
Oh, it's all right.
Ah, but...
- It's all good, Hina, really.
- [Hina] Hm.
Geez, Hina. What was that all about?
Nothing.
I'm just too excited. That's all.
GYMNASTICS CLUB
JULY
WINNER
[panting]
I'm running so late.
Why'd it have to be today?
I don't wanna miss a single second!
[sighs] It started already.
I guess I'll try to find the others.
CANDY APPLES
SOLD OUT
No way! That was all I cared about!
Oh, well.
I need to make sacrifices
so I can do my best in gymnastics.
I should give up going out with friends
and trying the food stands,
eating candy apples...
Give up...
Here you go.
[gasps]
They sent me to buy stuff for everybody.
And this was the last one. Here.
Well, thank you.
But how did you even know
that I wanted one?
I happened to notice
you were drooling before.
Wait! You saw that?
I sure did. You made such a weird face.
Hey! Leave me alone!
Look at us now.
And you're still committing
acts of violence against me.
What?
We've been so busy
that we haven't gone
to the festival since.
I forgot how much fun we had.
[slow music playing]
I should get back.
So let's go again.
[Taiki] Hm?
This year, you and me.
We should go together.
[slow music ends]
Let's go to the fireworks festival.
[exclaims softly]
Sure.
For real?
Inomata! I think
you just missed a phone call.
The buzzing was getting annoying.
[Taiki] Oh, thanks. Sorry about that.
We'll talk details later.
Yeah, sounds good.
- Why don't we head back?
- Yeah.
FIREWORKS FESTIVAL
[Niina] Oh, look, the fireworks festival
is coming up.
- What are you doing? Wanna go together?
- [Hina] Ah...
I'm sorry, Niina, I went and made plans
with someone else already.
With who?
So is it a date or...
[Hina] No!
[Niina] Guy plus girl plus fireworks...
Definitely a date.
It isn't like that. Really.
He's only ever thought of me
as his friend.
[Niina chuckles]
Well, I hope you have fun.
[exclaims softly]
- [Niina] Sorry that I interrupted earlier.
- There's nothing going on with Taiki!
[Niina] Yeah, okay.
[insects trilling]
[Yukiko] Three weeks until
Chinatsu goes to nationals, huh?
- So, are you feeling ready?
- As I'll ever be.
Do let me know if you need anything, okay?
You'll be there a few nights, right?
I can buy what you need
if you make me a list.
I really appreciate it.
Oh. The fireworks festival
is next weekend.
Do you think you'll go?
I might stop by for a bit.
I have a yukata for you.
[Taiki] I am trying to keep my distance
over here and focus on my homework!
How could you bring up such a distraction?
[Yukiko] It's a bit old,
but really pretty.
[Chinatsu] Oh, no. I'm okay.
[grunts]
- [Yukiko] What about you, Taiki?
- Mm?
Are you going to go to the festival?
Yeah, with some friends.
Don't do anything wild, okay?
[Taiki] Actually, who else is even coming?
I should probably see if Kyo can come.
Hina is not really the organizing type.
All right, then the rest of us
will go over to Yokoi's,
and watch the fireworks from there.
But that's the ultimate viewing spot mom!
I'll have to bring some booze!
Don't rub it in my face!
- [Yukiko] We are adults after all.
- Well, we're gonna have soft drinks!
[shuttlecock thudding]
[pants]
That was a productive practice.
Thanks, Taiki.
[Taiki] Somehow
Haryu's gotten even better lately.
[Haryu sighs]
[Taiki] The way things are going,
I'll never catch up to him.
- By the way...
- What do you want now?
You already beat me, don't make it worse.
You don't have to be so hostile, bro.
I'm not hostile!
So on the 31st,
I'll be meeting up
with a friend of mine at his practice.
He's on the university team. Wanna come?
University team?
Yeah they're ranked pretty high up,
so it's gonna be intense.
I'll be there!
[water running]
- [turns off tap]
- [chuckles softly]
[yelps]
Why are you grinning at yourself?
Hina! Do you always
need to sneak up on me?
You were smiling in the mirror,
and I couldn't help myself.
You spend a lot of your time
goofy-grinning, you know.
- You're such a daydreamer.
- Nuh-uh!
I was invited
to practice with a university team.
So I'm just feeling excited.
I have to make the most
of this opportunity
with everyone about to go to nationals.
It's the same day
as the fireworks festival,
but I'll be there in time, okay?
[Hina] Okay.
I have practice, too, anyway.
[Taiki] I can't wait.
These festivals have the best yakisoba.
Must be the grills they use.
So carbs before beauty, right?
By the way,
who else is gonna be in our group?
Huh?
[grunts]
Uh... uh...
I forgot to invite other people. Whoopsie!
For real?
Taiki, why don't you go ahead
and invite Kyo for me?
And I'll reach out to my friends
and see who can make it.
Thanks for your help.
[Taiki] She paused. What was that?
[whimpers]
Can't believe I messed up asking him out.
The fireworks festival?
Sure, I'm down to join you.
It's gonna be great.
Let's meet at 6:00.
Wait, I thought you were going
to the university practice
with Haryu that day.
It's okay, I can make it to both of them.
[Kyo] Aren't you a busy man,
squeezing two big events into one day.
[Taiki] It's just one day.
And I wanna go to both.
So who else is coming
with us to the festival?
[Taiki] Hina, for one.
It was her idea, actually.
Although, it sounds like
she forgot to invite other people,
so she told me to invite you.
[Kyo] That's probably because
she wanted to go with you, alone!
All right! Let's get going.
[Kyo] I mean, good for her
for mustering up
the courage to ask him out at all.
But getting psyched up to go for it
is useless if she's not clear!
She's made a mess of this.
What? What do you mean
you already made plans
to go to the fireworks festival
with your hometown friends?
Well, yeah, you said
you'd found someone to go with.
True, but you could've spent
a little more time
feeling bad about the fact
that you couldn't go with me!
Okay, rude.
Did something happen
with the guy you asked out?
Don't tell me he said no.
We are going together.
But he, apparently,
thinks we're going as a group.
Go clarify with him.
Say you just meant you two.
No way.
Just asking him if we could go together
used up all the courage I have, Niina.
And if he turns me down,
that could potentially
affect our friendship.
[sighs]
It's your fault for still playing
the best friend role.
Wait, my fault?
Hang on, you said "best friend."
Who do you think we're talking about!
[Niina] Is she actually trying
to keep it a secret?
So about the festival.
[Chinatsu] Yeah.
[Nagisa] As of right now, Mariko, Sana,
and Akari are planning on coming.
[Chinatsu] Awesome!
So should we... invite guys?
You never know, maybe a couple of us
will hit it off in the romance department.
And they can be shields
so we don't get hit on.
[Chinatsu] Mm.
Just girls is fine with me.
I think it'll be harder
to get a good spot in a big group.
Yeah you're right.
Okay, we'll make it just us girls then.
[Chinatsu] Besides, that isn't really
something I need right now.
[Hina] Taiki!
Hm?
Getting more birdies?
We burn through 'em pretty quick.
Summer practices are pretty long
for both of us, aren't they?
With nationals coming up,
be careful not to get injured.
Mm-hm.
Plus, there's the fireworks festival
to look forward to.
Oh, yeah, Kyo can come with us.
Great!
That's just great.
What about you?
Did you invite anyone?
It sounds like everyone I know
has a lot of friends.
[chuckles]
So the same group as always, then.
Taiki, be honest with me.
Did you actually want to go with Chinatsu?
It wouldn't have worked.
We could never go to a place
as crowded as a festival,
because someone could spot us together.
And even if I asked her out,
I'm certain that
she would've turned me down.
Because she told you that the two of you
should keep your distance?
No need to revisit that unpleasant moment.
I thought that she and I had gotten close
over the past few months.
I just wanted to get even closer to her.
But it was only me
who was feeling that way.
I don't really understand where
the boundaries are so I don't overstep.
I'm scared that one wrong move
is going to make her not like me.
Or that I'll come face-to-face again
with the fact that
I'm the only one with feelings.
And what's worse...
is that the closer I get to her,
the bigger that fear gets.
Huh?
- Let's go the other way.
- What?
Uh... [sighs]
[groans]
Hey, that was really violent,
even for you--
- This isn't like you!
- Huh?
I get you not wanting
to bother the girl you like,
and not wanting
to ruin your friendship with her.
I get how those thoughts are making you
afraid to move forward...
But Taiki...
you looking out for others' feelings
as well as your own...
and always staying positive...
that's what...
[stammers]
that's what makes you great.
But you're a loser
for sneaking around and avoiding her!
Uncool!
See you later.
Geez, what's up with her?
I've never seen her like that before.
[Haryu] Taiki. Over here!
Hi, everyone.
[Taiki gasps]
Hyodo?
Why's he here?
He's gonna be a student here next year,
so he's coming in to practice
with them from time to time.
[inaudible]
[inspirational music playing]
[grunts]
[pants]
This is intense.
Way beyond our normal practice.
Even Haryu looks like he's exhausted.
Want some?
Because you're staring.
It does have my germs.
Oh, no! I'm fine, thank you!
Cool. Nevermind.
[Taiki] He seems pretty friendly.
You know, you tend to get tense
whenever you're under pressure.
Huh?
You were pulling back your right elbow
right before you'd strike.
Stay relaxed till the shuttle
actually hits your strings.
[Taiki] Like this?
Yeah, that's it.
Loosen your wrist, and focus on the angle
instead of on power.
Hey, can you feed him one?
You got it.
[grunts]
[Taiki] That felt great!
Nice shot, dude.
[Taiki exclaims softly]
If you'd swung like that before,
you could've scored more points on Yusa.
In your doubles matches, I thought
you got in some pretty good shots.
But in singles,
you were stiff and always on defense.
The way you were constantly moving around
was a total waste.
There are two slots
for nationals next year.
If you stay where you're at...
my money's on Haryu and Yusa to go.
What do you think?
[Taiki] Why is he asking me about this?
I guess I agree.
And that makes my own goals clearer.
Haryu is my practice partner.
He represents what I want to become.
And after losing the other day,
Yusa is the one
I want to beat in a rematch.
Knowing what I need to focus on...
It's good to have that clarity.
I'm no match for either of them
at this point.
[grunts]
But I'm better
when I have a goal to chase down.
[gasps softly]
How 'bout you warn me next time? Yeah?
[Taiki] I'm sorry! I can feed next.
[Hyodo] He makes some good points,
but he's barely got a fighting chance.
The ones other players
strive to be are on top
'cause they know how to deliver.
But...
everybody loves to root
for the underdog, don't they?
[inspirational music ends]
[trembling]
Nice effort today.
Come by any time.
Did Hyodo leave?
[boy] Yeah, he went home.
[Haryu] The next time I see him
will be at nationals.
Taiki, got any plans?
I'm supposed to meet Kyo and Hina at 6:00.
KYO
SORRY, GOT A FEVER. CAN'T GO TODAY
A fever?
Hey, bro!
Are you feeling okay?
YOU OKAY?
KYO
YOU PASSED IT ON TO ME
WHEN?
KYO
YOU TWO HAVE FUN
[gasps]
[inaudible]
[slow music playing]
Okay, calm down. Calm down.
The two of us have been
hanging out alone for years now!
HINA
I'M STILL IN
[Taiki] This place is a zoo.
I wonder if I'm even gonna find her.
HINA
SORRY, RUNNING LATE!
It's one thing after another.
Well, she did say
she had practice today, too.
[gasps]
My heart almost stopped.
[sighs]
That really freaked me out.
I've got goals
in the romance department, too.
But it's harder than badminton,
'cause the other person
has to feel the same.
CANDY APPLES
300 YEN
If memory serves, Hina likes those.
Why don't I get her one!
[woman] Here you are. Thank you very much.
[Hina] Is that... for me?
You better believe
you're gonna pay me back, tho-- [gasps]
[slow music climaxes]
What is it?
Uh...
It... was...
You owe me 300 yen.
[Hina] Okay.
[closing theme song playing]